we're gonna get to this in alarm room
after the retreat okay but meditation 15
when I was in Thailand you know and we
gave everybody refugee bow and refuge
name then people get all excited you
know
and they running around with their new
name and they're showing everybody look
I have a new name
mine's cooler than yours you know he
gave he gave me this one special I'm not
like you you know and everybody start
wearing you can see in the Beijing
Airport you know suddenly everyone's
wearing these rosaries like ten years
ago nobody now even the business guys
are are wearing these groceries and yoga
teachers like to do that I noticed when
I go to yoga they're all wearing the
rosary on the wrong hand
they're the right hand you always wear
it on your left hand because then you
can debate you know but uh so it means
people like to once they take refuge or
something they like to use the
accoutrement the the cute little Dharma
things you know look I have Beats my
beads have turquoise on them you know or
I have crystal you have wood you know or
I have gold on my beats but you yours
are just metal you know or I have my my
I have a refuge name and youth um you
know or you know it means the outer
things that are associated with
spirituality and people like them some
people where religious clothes you know
like red clothes or white clothes or
clothes and they get very attached to
them you know I have I have there's a
gash a Duncan vest it has a yellow
stripe on it here you know and in the
monastery it's very important you know
if you have - a yellow stripe here
everyone's like Oh getting like gala you
know I refuse to wear this you never saw
me wear it
I have one but it's too small it was
made for Tibetan anyway and people get
very attached to it you know if you wear
it and you also in the tantric college
you get a special one and if you wear it
when you're not supposed to wear it
everyone gets upset you know you're not
supposed to wear that you know so what I
like about the Neo Tom copy and lineage
that we have the newts on copper lineage
that we have is we are not very big on
these outer you know science like I have
yellow stripe you don't have yellow
stripe you know I have llama hat you
don't have llama head you know I like it
that we are disguised as someone who
owns a cosmetics company in Singapore
you know like everybody thinks I'm just
normal person you know and I think
that's very healthy
we don't have hierarchy we don't have
big llama little Big Momma big little
llama you know we don't have these
things you know and we don't have people
running in so you you shouldn't do like
this you should put your fingers inside
or you're a bad person you know I like
it that we don't have all these silly
things you know I'm happy we don't have
this
okay we we're working on the inside to
try to be a nice person
okay so meditation number 15 is to think
about that you know in my attach to you
know everybody sees my beads and they
know I'm a spiritual person or you know
am I trying to impress people with my
Tibetan grammar skills like getting
Michael does you know this outer thing
okay it's not an inner thing look how
much scripture I can quote you know look
how many words I can look up in John's
database you know who could find that
story that I told you this morning these
are all outer things okay
so what he's talking about
are the outer signs of taking refuge
okay beads name special hats you know
outer signs that you took refuge and and
what he says is stick to the what's it's
a second husband second husband refuse
okay nobody knows you're doing it okay
you're like oh this person irritate me
oh wait it's like second husband come
from me you know there's a joke at
Diamond Mountain there's a joke and
somebody came from another place they
came to Diamond Mountain they said I
can't believe it what everybody I meet
is so stupid
I'm surrounded by stupid people then
that all Diamond Mountain people go
[Music]
understand okay so yeah take a real
refuse okay and nobody knows if you took
refuge or not okay you understand
emptiness and it's very quiet and nobody
can prove it
people come to me all the time I think I
saw emptiness I said okay tell me what
it's like I saw a green light yellow
I'll forget it you want to hear a real
conversation are your conversation I
think I saw you didn't I said no okay
one of the experience one of the
qualities of seeing emptiness is
directly is that you are sure you did it
nobody you don't have to ask anybody
okay and and the whole world can tell
you you didn't and you don't care you
know it's the big big big Lamas can say
you didn't and you say okay I didn't but
I did not only you know and and you know
for sure so if you're not sure you did
it when you do you do when you do you
know and it doesn't matter what anyone
says you you know the world can't blow
up and you don't care I saw it I I know
tell me anything I don't care you know
okay so if you have to ask you dude all
right all right